AHUL VADDI

3+ years of experience in tech, with more than 1.6 years focus on Azure DevOps, Azure services, and FastAPI development. Skilled in containerization (Docker) and orchestration (Kubernetes), optimizing application scalability and deployment. Experience in AI/ML model deployment, testing Sensor Interface KPI tools, and UI development with PyQt Designer.











WORK EXPERIENCE

Bosch Global Software Technologies

Cloud Engineer - ADAS Technology

January 2023 - Present

- Developed and Deployed Microservices: Implemented Python back-end logic using FastAPI for ML model inferencing, containerized modules using Docker, and deployed them in a microservices architecture with
- Azure Container Registry (ACR) and Kubernetes for orchestration.

 Automated CI/CD and Workflow Management: Built automated deployment pipelines and used Apache Airflow for workflow orchestration, creating DAGs to manage and automate data workflows and task execution.

Bosch Global Software Technologies

Backend developer

July 2022 - December 2023

- Developed and Deployed Scalable AI/ML Tool: Built a tool for AI/ML model deployment using FastAPI, Docker, and cloud migration techniques, hosted on Azure Cloud. Deployed Azure Web App Service for automatic
- Secaling and load balancing.

 Version Control and Documentation: Utilized Git in Azure DevOps for source code management and created an endpoint for a pre-trained model in Azure Machine Learning Studio, documenting the deployment and inference process in the organization's wiki

Bosch Global Software Technologies

Software test engineer

September 2021 - June 2022

I began my first full-time professional journey as Software Test Engineer. My role was to test sensor Validation Tool. I have performed thorough manual testing to ensure the tool functions as expected, including unit testing, integration testing and Documentation Review

EDUCATION

Vellore Institute of Technology

Master of Technology (Integrated), Software Engineering

June 2016 - July 2021

Narayana Institute

June 2014 - April 2016

Intermediate Kendriya Vidyalaya

Class X

April 2013 - March 2014

PROJECTS

Commuter Flow Projection based on Long Short-Term Memory | RNN

November 2020

The motive of this project to analyse the statistical data characteristics of historical passenger flow is the premise basis for proposing the prediction scheme, improving the prediction method and obtaining more accurate

Driver Sleep Detection System | Artificial Intelligence, DL

April 2020

The motive of this project is to locate, track and analyse both the driver's face and eyes to compute a drowsiness index to prevent accidents.

Celkart Management System | Summer Internship | CSS, DJANGO, HTML5, PYTHON

May 2019

The motive of this project is to meet the demands of modern online shoppers while providing sellers with the tools they need to succeed in the digital marketplace and to show best offers to the customers. Used python programming language to implement backend logic, and API integrations and while employing frontend technologies like HTML, CSS for the user interface

SKILLS

- Architecture: Microservices. Backend: Python, RESTful APIs.
- Cloud Development: Azure App Services, Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), Azure Container Registry (ACR). Cloud DevOps: Azure DevOps for CI/CD pipelines, Docker, Kubernetes, Service Connections. Cloud Infrastructure: Azure Blob Storage.

 Databases: MongoDB.

- Data Engineering: Apache Airflow (ETL).
 Frameworks/Technologies: FastAPI, GitHub.
 Monitoring & Observability: Grafana, Prometheus.
 Operating Systems: Windows, Linux.
- Scripting: Bash (Shell).

CERTIFICATE

Azure DevOps crash course



Azure Devops and Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) release pipelines

LANGUAGE

English Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi Full Professional Proficiency

Telugu Native/Bilingual Proficiency

AWARD

Rockstar Bosch Global Software Technologies

This award reflects my proactive approach, collaborative spirit, and unwavering commitment to project's success

Extra Miler Bosch Global Software Technologies Awarded Extra Miler for being active part of a team.

Shout out Bosch Global Software Technologies Received Shout out Award for my active contributions.

EXTRA CIRCULAR